cardio yoga strength training even
meditation these are just a few of the
workout classes at your disposal with
the mirror now it's no secret that
interactive smart gyms are pretty much
all the rage right now in the fitness
Community I've been using the mirror for
a little while so today I'm gonna break
down my findings for you guys
what's up everybody it's Jake back in my
natural habitat aka the barbin garage
gym for today's video I've got the
mirror now in this review I'm going to
walk you through everything you need to
know about this piece of equipment from
the price and the features as well as
some pros and cons you'll experience
while working out with it and of course
who should or maybe should not buy it
now before we get started today we have
reviewed a decent amount of smart gems
on barbin.com if you want to learn more
about our top picks just Google barbin
best smart gyms you can find out for
yourself which one we like the best
[Applause]
okay so there's a lot to like about
mirror first and foremost it's a
state-of-the-art piece of technology and
it's compatible with your phone so once
you download the companion app you can
control everything mirror does from your
phone you can pick and choose which
classes that you want to join it's
loaded with over 50 different Fitness
categories so there's really an option
for everybody out there there's also a
daily live schedule of classes for you
to join but if you can't join those for
whatever reason you can always join them
in an on-demand fashion later on and
there's also workout programs for you to
choose from depending on what your
fitness goals are and for me personally
I really like to compete so during those
live classes there's a leaderboard
function and I really like that because
it's going to push me and make me try
even harder during those classes
okay so now with all that being said
there were a few issues that I noticed
that you also might notice let's talk
about money first this one's repriced
right around fifteen hundred dollars and
it does not include any accessories so
if that's what you're focused on you
want your purchase to come with
accessories but I have to spend a little
bit more money up front or you can
always add them on over time but that
might make you spend more money in the
long run you do have to pair the mirror
to your phone and you know it could be a
problem for some people you want to make
sure you're pretty close to your Wi-Fi
router now we're in a garage that
initial pairing of the two was a little
difficult now it's totally fine but in
the beginning it was a little tough so
keep that in mind
and if you're somebody who wants to have
a really high emphasis on strength
training and weight lifting this might
not be the ideal product for you it's
more so focused around overall Fitness
in my opinion
okay so I touched on price with our
specific model that we have right here
but let's dig into more of that now so
when you head over to the mirror website
there's four different packages for you
to choose from I'll dig into what each
package includes in just a minute but
for now just know that the basic package
is going to cost you right around 1500
bucks the essentials is right around
1700 the pro package is right around
eighteen hundred dollars and the family
package is going to run you near two
grand it's also worth mentioning that
just to gain access to the classes you
do have to sign up for a subscription
it's gonna charge you forty dollars a
month and if you're interested in those
personal training classes I talked about
you have to pay per session which is
also forty dollars now mirror is going
to deliver and install your device for
you for no additional charge and if you
want you can also split up your purchase
into monthly payments of either 12 24 or
48 months which is pretty nice
now when it comes to finding out which
package is the best for you really just
personal preference and you know your
personal situation but just for example
if you're living by yourself and you
don't have any accessories already and
maybe that's important to you I would
suggest just going with the pro package
it's only a hundred dollars more than
the essentials and you do get you know
some extra accessories however if you're
living with somebody you know a friend
also or maybe they want to come over and
use your mirror family member really
whatever it may be I would suggest going
with the family package because you're
both going to get your own set of
accessories to work out with
okay so let's talk a little bit more now
about that monthly membership that I
mentioned so once again once you have
your mirror set up you're ready to get
working out you are required to sign up
for a monthly membership it's going to
cost you 40 bucks a month with a one
year minimum membership cool thing is
though you can invite up to five
additional people to essentially share
that membership and split everything up
six different ways in terms of money so
that's pretty cool now as far as
inviting your friends goes it's a pretty
simple process just head over to the
settings tab click on household members
click on invite and then type in the
email address you want to send a
download link to so once your friend
gets the email all they have to do is
click on the download Now link follow
the instructions and honestly from there
it's just super easy to follow along and
get their profile set up
[Music]
okay remember those accessories I was
talking about all right well now I'm
gonna break down what each package
includes what accessories are going to
come with them so for starters let's
talk about the basic package and as you
might assume it's pretty basic it
doesn't come with anything other than
the stand and the lens cap to cover your
camera when necessary the essentials
package though that's going to come with
the stand and the lens cap a heart rate
monitor a fitness band pack a reversible
floor mat Loop it up matte strap lift
and lengthen yoga block as well as a
foam roller the pro package is going to
have everything the essentials package
has with the addition of a towel as well
as a pair of dumbbells of your choosing
and those range from one pound to 35
pounds
now if there's more than one person
working out with mirror the family
package is probably going to be the way
to go for you because you're going to
get two of every accessory I just
mentioned other than that foam roller it
is worth mentioning though that the
ankle weights aren't included with any
of the packages which might be a bummer
for some people you have to add that on
separately if you want those but you
don't have to have any of these if you
don't want them or maybe you already
have all of these maybe just some of
them you don't have to have any of them
it is nice though that ankle weights and
the dumbbells are going to track your
reps during any exercise that requires
those
okay so let's talk a little bit more
about the accessories now say you went
with that basic package and you want to
add on your accessories over time or you
know maybe you just need a couple of
them you can purchase all these
individually whenever you want so
starting with the ankle weights you have
two different options that one pound
pair is going to cost you right around
80 bucks while that two pound pair is
just under a hundred dollars once again
the dumbbells range from 1 to 35 pounds
so the price for each pair you go with
it's going to vary just depending on
which one you go with so the one pound
pair is listed right around 50 bucks
while that 35 pound pair of dumbbells
that's going to be right around 200 the
towel is going to cost you around 40
bucks the yoga mat that's eighty dollars
the loop it up Matt strap can actually
double as a carrier for your yoga mat
that as well as the yoga block are both
twenty dollars and the foam roller
that's 40 bucks there's also a starter
kit for you to buy it's going to include
some resistance bands as well as a heart
rate monitor that's gonna be right
around 100 bucks or you can purchase
either one of those separately for you
know right around fifty dollars a piece
there's also a care kit if you don't
have anything to clean your mirror it's
going to include everything necessary to
do that for right around 20 bucks and as
you're scrolling you're going to see a
good amount of clothing items from
shorts to shirts to yoga pants those are
all made by Lululemon with the mirror
branding on them
so I mentioned there's 50 different
Fitness categories for you to choose
from but there's also around 10
000 classes at your disposal so you can
spend the day in a kickboxing class if
you want maybe bust out some dumbbells
or even just take some time to meditate
the point is as Tony Montana would say
it the world is yours it can be a little
overwhelming to decide what you want to
do though so thankfully there is a Time
Savers tab where you can quickly scroll
through the available classes and I
personally love the weekly drop feature
because it just recommends classes that
are based off of your workout history
foreign
okay so let's talk about the build now
with the mirror the frame is pretty
durable it's made from carbon steel and
it has a powder coat which I personally
think it's going to make it match really
any room it could go in now the screen
is obviously made from glass so you
definitely run the risk of it breaking
so you obviously want to put it
somewhere as safe as possible it comes
with a wall mount as well as a stand I
would suggest just keeping it on the
stand though like we have in case you
ever want to move it around your home
for whatever reason it weighs 70 pounds
when it's on the sand it's right around
65 inches tall without it it's about 56
inches
it's right around 22 inches wide and it
has a depth of right around 1.5 inches
okay so let's talk about some of the
features now with mirror there is an iOS
as well as an Android companion app for
you to download this is essential
because while it might look like it
mirror is not touch screen so you're
gonna have to download that app to
control everything that mirror has to
offer it does have Bluetooth
capabilities for you to connect a heart
rate monitor or Fitness tracker you can
connect your Apple music or your Spotify
account so you can play your own music
through the speakers while you're
working out
it was a 43 inch 1080p display it's
going to give you crystal clear picture
while you're working out of your
instructor and I'll dig into this
feature more in just a second but I
really like the health score this is all
based on how much you work out and it's
going to increase with each individual
workout that you complete
let's talk about technology I really
like the fact you have a camera located
at the top of the mirror because this is
going to be great during those personal
training classes since your personal
trainer can see you and correct your
form whenever necessary don't worry
though this isn't some 1984 Big Brother
thing you can always cover the camera
whenever you want with that lens cap
like we have on ours right now the
companion app is essential I got to make
sure you understand that you Gotta Have
It mirror is not touch screen so can't
do anything with it if you don't have
that app downloaded there's a quad core
processor within the mirror now I'm not
a tech wizard trust me it's not my job
but
it's perfect for technology such as this
it's going to make all the commands that
you're you know telling the mirror to do
really fast and I already talked about
Bluetooth a little bit you can connect
to heart rate monitor as well as a
fitness tracker but you can also pair
mirror to a Bluetooth speaker so you can
have your instructor coming through the
speaker and music coming through the
mirror or vice versa whatever you want
okay so let's take a quick walk around
with the mirror now starting with your
camera it's located right up here at the
Top If you ever want to cover it though
you do have this lens cap just pop it on
you can also slide it back and forth if
you don't want to remove it you don't
have to the frame is made from carbon
steel it has a nice powder coat on it I
personally think it gives it a nice
little color and it's going to make it
match really any room you might put it
in but since the display is made from
glass you obviously want to be really
careful with it and store it somewhere
as safe as possible because I really
doubt you want this to break on you your
power button is located down here at the
bottom I left the sticker on so you can
see it
it's really easy it's not too much to it
you just press the button to turn it on
and off whenever it's plugged in your
speakers are located towards the bottom
on the back right here and you do need a
three prong outlet to plug this in now
the cord's not very long so unless
you're using a really solid extension
cord you know I would recommend just
finding yourself an outlet that's
relatively close to your device
okay so who should purchase the mirror
well anybody that's looking to get
personal training without leaving the
comfort of their home I think you're
really going to love the fact that there
is a camera at the top it's gonna be
awesome and it allows your personal
trainer to see you during those classes
and correct your form when necessary if
you're new to Fitness you don't really
know what you're doing all the time I
think you'll like the fact that you know
each class is in fact instructed and
your instructor is going to tell you how
to perform each exercise the correct way
if you're like myself you really Thrive
off competition I think the leaderboard
function is something you'll really like
as well it's going to push you and make
you try that much harder in my opinion I
know it does for me and the fact that
the footprint is almost non-existent and
it resembles an actual mirror I think
this is a really good option for the
majority of really everyone especially
people who are kind of tight on Space
because you can put this almost anywhere
okay so who should not purchase mirror
then well
price is a pretty big factor in my
opinion you know the cheapest version is
that basic package right around 1500
bucks and you still got to pay that
monthly membership of forty dollars a
month I will say though in the long run
it's probably gonna pay for itself you
know especially when you compare you
know going to a gym as well as any
personal training sessions you might be
booking
if you're somebody who wants to have a
high emphasis and strength training and
muscle building it probably isn't the
product for you now don't get me wrong
you can definitely get a solid workout
in you'll feel the burn but you know the
dumbbells only go up to 35 pounds and I
really felt as if this was more so based
around overall Fitness and not
necessarily muscle building
kind of sticking with that here if you
want your product to come with a good
amount of starter weights I mean you're
just not going to get that here unless
you get that family package that's the
only way you're getting more than one
pair of dumbbells with your purchase so
if that's something that you really need
or want I'd suggest you know going with
a different smart gym maybe tonal or
even tempo
foreign
puts a wrap on today's review over the
mirror this is a really cool piece of
equipment and it's about as futuristic
as you can ask it to be maybe other than
being touch screen the ability to join
live on demand and even sign up for
personal one-on-one training sessions
really makes it to where you can find a
class and a workout at any given moment
throughout the day plus you can stream
everything from your phone so if you're
out of town you can still get your
workout in and if you're like myself I
think you'll really enjoy the fact that
the live classes do have that
leaderboard function so you can compete
thanks for watching everybody hope this
video was helpful and that I was able to
tell you more about what Mir has to
offer stay on the lookout for my next
review but for now head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
this product right here just search bar
Bend mirror review and you can read over
everything I discussed here today I'll
see y'all next time foreign
[Music]